<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog | Sukhdev Singh on </title>
    <link>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog | Sukhdev Singh on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 16:17:21 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimum Spanning Tree - Prims Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/minimum_spanning_tree_-_prims_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 13:40:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/minimum_spanning_tree_-_prims_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Hello, Today we are going to learn about the Prims algorithm of finding a minium spanning tree. If you don’t know what is a minium spanning tree then please go and study about it on this blog post.
So Prims algoritms says that start from a random vertex from tree put it in tree. Find all the neighbours of all the nodes in the tree excluding the one&amp;rsquo;s which are already in the tree.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acid Properties of Transactions</title>
      <link>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/acid_properties_of_transactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 08:14:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/acid_properties_of_transactions/</guid>
      <description>Hello,
Today we will learn about the acid properties of a Transaction.
ACID is an acronym for Atomicity Consestency Isonlation Durability.
Let&amp;rsquo;s understand what is the use of ACID properties. So if atransaction is intracting with the database, then there&amp;rsquo;s a change that it might make the database inconsistent or maybe result in data loss. This is where ACID properties comes in picture. ACID properties assure that the transaction will change the database such that it will still remain in a consistent state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimum Spanning Tree - Krushkal Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/minium_spanning_tree_-_krushkal_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 00:03:01 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/minium_spanning_tree_-_krushkal_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Hello, Today we are going to learn about the krushkal algorithm of finding a minium spanning tree. If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what is a minium spanning tree then please go and study about it on this blog post.
The krushkal&amp;rsquo;s aglorithm says that you have to pick the edge
 which has least weight in the graph, wont make cycle in the tree  And after that pick the next edge which is second lightest in weight, then third, then fourth&amp;hellip;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transactions in Dbms</title>
      <link>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/transactions_in_dbms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 19:19:18 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/transactions_in_dbms/</guid>
      <description>Hello, Today we are going to learn about Transactions in Database.
Transaction is basicallly a set of instruction. A group of cammands that perform some operations on the database. Let&amp;rsquo;s understand it this way, You have written a js programm like this
fs.writeFileSync(&amp;#39;./sample.txt&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Hello&amp;#39;) console.log(&amp;#39;Half message sent!!&amp;#39;); fs.writeFileSync(&amp;#39;./sample.txt&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;World&amp;#39;) Now in this code each line is a instruction to javascript that do a specific task.
As in first line we said that, &amp;ldquo;Hey Javascript, write &amp;lsquo;Hello&amp;rsquo; in a file names &amp;lsquo;sample.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Types in C</title>
      <link>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/data_types_in_c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:21:15 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/data_types_in_c/</guid>
      <description>Hello,
Today, we will learn about data types in C. So what are types?
To understand it better, let&amp;rsquo;s see what&amp;rsquo;s variable. Variable is just a virtual box that can hold some stuff. In computing that, stuff is some data, like Integer (3, 4) or character (&amp;lsquo;s&amp;rsquo;), etc. So data type is property/attribute of that box which specify which kind of stuff/data this box can hold.
There are many different types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a C Program</title>
      <link>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/how_to_write_a_c_program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 16:50:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sukhiboi.github.io/blog/how_to_write_a_c_program/</guid>
      <description>Hello,
I know you came here to understand how to write a C program. But before we write a C program, I think first we should learn some basic things about C.
Well C was developed by Dennis M. Ritchie and first implemented in 1972 at Bell Labs. C is a language that deals with low-level stuff like memory, but the exciting part is that it is written in a high-level language.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>